Yuan LYU

UX/Interaction Designer

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design Double Degree

Technical University Berlin, Germany

Oct.2016 ~ Present

University Paris-Sud, France

Sep.2015 ~ Jun.2016

Minor Innovation and Entrepreneurship

EIT Digital Master School

Sep. 2015 ~ Present

😭 EIT Digital Merit Scholarship 2016/2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering

Dalian Maritime University, China

Sep.2011 ~ Jun.2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Design Working Student, Care Campanion GmbH.
 Product Team, Berlin, Germany
 Jul.2017 ~ Present

- Concepting and designing for main website and new landing page
- Analyzing user journey, preparing&executing user research activities
- Co-operating with senior designer, product managers and developer

Product Support Working Student, Jovoto GmbH.

Product Team, Berlin, Germany

Mar.2017 ~ May.2017

- Created user flows and wireframes for products concept papers
- Technically translated internal as well as external bug reports
- Validated and enriched bug reports with all needed information

UX Intern, FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd.

Innovation Institute, Ningbo, China

Oct.2014 ~ Jan.2015

- Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven
- Implement the high-fidelity Prototype
- Made reasonable user test script, participated in usability research

PROJECTS

UI/UX Designer, Bingo for elders

Quality&Usability Project, Berlin, Germany Oct.2016 ~ Mar.2017

- In charge of UI Design and User test for this Android tablet game.

APP Designer & Technical Support, Transmetics

Start-up Project, Paris, France

Sep.2015 ~ May.2016

- Run a project as a start-up, in charge of APP Design, Android platform development, user test and market analysis.

- +49(0)157-3326-2956
- yuan.lyu@hotmail.com
- http://yuan-lyu.com
- Berlin, Germany 10963

PROFILE

As a hybrid designer with programming experience, I am adept at understanding of user story, and always have the passion to use my creativity to solve unusual problems and design for uncommon products.

Currently look forward to a position in the area of Interaction or UX Design.

SKILLS

DESIGN

In-Depth Interview
Questionnaire
Persona | Scenario
Conceptual Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Test
Sketch/Photoshop
Axture/InVision
Balsamiq/OmniGraffle

PROGRAMMING

JAVA/C#
HTML/CSS
ASP.NET
SQL Server/MySQL
JavaScript
Arduino
Node.js

LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native English: Fluent

German/Italian: Beginner